Matt Prestlien

+1 (360) 303-6901 mprestlien@me.com http://mattprestlien.com/

Denver, CO 80205

Profile

Professional and versatile engineer with a penchant for security-driven design hailing from veteran SaaS firms. Experience and acute interest in mobile web app development and design, specifically with React/Redux and Cordova. Works proficiently alone and adeptly within group or team dynamics, coupled with excellent time management skills and attention to detail.

Experience

Cordova Engineer, SpiderOak; Kansas City, MO (Remote) - 2016-Present

Focused on building an end-to-end encrypted enterprise chat application, I quickly picked up Semaphor's cutting edge tech stack. With my Cordova expertise I have been able to quickly and efficiently solve performance/UX issues and implement features with Sass, css-modules and breakpoints to create a React/Redux mobile app maintaining a well-organized codebase that is responsive enough to be deployed on the desktop via Electron. My implementations have been commended by team members for their accuracy to mockups while ensuring users know how their data is handled without the need to decipher technical jargon.

Software Engineer, ServiceMonster; Bellingham, WA - 2014-2016

As the sole team member focused on mobile, I began by translating an ASP.net application to a mobile app. I chose frameworks and technologies carefully to ensure that the product could be built rapidly and efficiently while still ensuring an intuitive end-user experience. I was also tasked with hiring team members and supporting them with FOSS developer software (GitLab, Sentry) via Docker.

Apple Service Specialist, CityMac; Bellingham, WA - 2012-2014

Worked as a trainer providing lessons centered around Apple devices, ultimately attaining the ability to explain complex technology topics in simpler terms.

Education

Associate in Liberal Studies, Whatcom Community College; Bellingham, WA - 2012-2015 Performed to a high standard in my science and programming courses; receiving positive reviews and a recommendation from CS faculty.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

A strong IT background has contributed to my problem-solving skills and engineering process. I have worked in JavaScript, C#, Java, Objective-C, and Swift, primarily within the context of mobile front-ends and their RESTful web services. I have also had exposure to newer systems languages like Go and Rust. I have a deep understanding of single-state application flow via Redux and a familiarity with stateless functional paradigms in ES6.

Communication

Work methodically with a team of individuals in order to achieve a common goal. Previous projects involved managing a small team and making design decisions according to stakeholder input. Current projects include peer review, refactoring and profiling as needed as well as building specs to ensure development projects are well-maintained and all possible security considerations are taken into account.

Technologies

- React/Redux
- Cordova/Electron
- JSX/Sass
- ES6+ (Babel w/ESLint)
- Webpack
- AngularJS 1 & 2
- Atlassian Ecosystem
- AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda)
- Docker